Okay, now that we've discussed the
spread operator, um, we can discuss
destructuring an array, which sounds
scary, but I promise you it isn't. So,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to get
rid of this code here, and I'm going to
create an array like this. So, let's say
we have an array that says superhero
Bruce, Wayne, Batman, and 20. If I
wanted to print out um Bruce, then I
might alert superhero at the zero
position.
Um, and if I want to print out Wayne,
I'd have to say superhero
at the one position. And that would
alert Bruce and then Wayne. So, I'm
going to save this and go live
and we get Bruce and then Wayne. And so,
if we come back over here, that works.
But wouldn't it be nice if we had just
access Bruce with first name and Wayne
with last name? um or maybe first last
identity and um number of villains
caught this month. Um well, we can the
way we do that is we use the keyword let
because we're going to create some
variables. Where we create them is
between these square braces. We're
saying we have an array and we want to
pull each item out of the array and put
it into a corresponding variable. So,
I'm going to put first, last, um,
identity, and
villain count, and I'm going to set it
equal to superhero. What this does is it
says K.
Take the first thing out of the
superhero array and put it into this
variable called first. Take the second
thing and put it into the second
variable. on the third thing and put it
in the third variable on the fourth
thing and put it in the fourth variable.
What this allows me to do is just allow
alert first and then alert last.
So if I save this and I go over, we get
Bruce and Wayne. And so in this way,
we're able to access each item in this
array by a variable name rather than
having to say superhero at the zero
position. So, but what if you only
wanted to do this for certain items?
What if we just want the first name and
the identity? Well, if we want to do
that, then
we'll say what you do is you just get
rid of the parts you don't want and you
leave the commas. So, I'm saying I want
the first one, nothing, and the third
one, and then nothing. So, if I save
this, and I alert first,
and then I alert identity.
If I save that and I come over, I get
Bruce and Batman. Um, because we said we
don't care about the one that comes
between the zero position and the two
position. We don't care about the one
position and we don't care about the
position that comes after the two
position. Meaning, we don't care about
the three position. We care about zero
and two. And in that way, we're able to
get just some of the things. Well, what
if
we want to grab the first two out and
then we still want the rest of them
stored in an array? Well, you can do
that as well. So, what you can do is you
say you want first and last
and then you can use the spread operator
that we just learned to say everything
else.
So now if we alert first, last, and then
everything else. If we save that, if we
come over here, we get Bruce.
Oh, where do I have identity? We'll
reload this page. We get Bruce, Wayne,
Batman, 20, meaning the rest of these
are still in an array called everything
else. Um, but we were able to pull out
first and last. And so that's how array
dstructuring works. You can pull out
just specific items. Um, and it's
important to know that you can use the
spread operator to say take all the
other items and throw them into a list.
Um, commonly you'll see this called
rest. Um, I called it everything else.
You could call it whatever you want, but
you say pull out the first item and the
second item and then pull out other
stuff. And then it takes the rest of the
array, however much of it is left, and
puts it in an array called other stuff,
which you can then use in the rest of
your